{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Popular Culture",
    "Term": "Prefinals",
    "Title": "Fifth Module",
    "LastModified": "17 May 2024",
    "Authors": [
      "Alexander Oro"
    ],
    "References": [
      "Any external links/handouts should be referenced here"
    ]
  },
  "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "What is the oldest form of information transfer, primarily through materials that can be held by a hand?",
      "answer": "Printed Media",
      "choices": [
        "Radio",
        "Podcast",
        "Comics",
        "Printed Media"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is attributed with the patent in the movable type which revolutionized printed media?",
      "answer": "Johannes Gutenberg",
      "choices": [
        "Nikola Tesla",
        "Guglielmo Marconi",
        "Johannes Gutenberg",
        "Henry Hermann"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where did the earliest printing press appear?",
      "answer": "China in the year 932",
      "choices": [
        "Germany in the year 1450",
        "China in the year 932",
        "Italy in the year 1600",
        "England in the year 1476"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What was perhaps the first national magazine in circulation in the Philippines?",
      "answer": "Philippine Magazine",
      "choices": [
        "Liwayway",
        "Philippine Magazine",
        "Pugad Baboy",
        "Trese"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What novel by Umberto Eco discusses how people can be swayed based on what they can read and see?",
      "answer": "Numero Zero",
      "choices": [
        "Numero Zero",
        "The Name of the Rose",
        "Foucault’s Pendulum",
        "The Island of the Day Before"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the Philippines’ first comic strip?",
      "answer": "Kenkoy",
      "choices": [
        "Darna",
        "Pupung",
        "Kenkoy",
        "Pugad Baboy"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who are the famous characters created by Mars Ravelo?",
      "answer": "Darna and Captain Barbell",
      "choices": [
        "Darna and Captain Barbell",
        "Pupung",
        "Kenkoy",
        "Pugad Baboy"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the creator of the comic strip “Pupung”?",
      "answer": "Washington “Tonton” Young",
      "choices": [
        "Washington “Tonton” Young",
        "Mars Ravelo",
        "Apolonio “Pol” Medina, Jr.",
        "Budjette Tan and Kajo Baldisimo"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the comic strip created by Apolonio “Pol” Medina, Jr.?",
      "answer": "Pugad Baboy",
      "choices": [
        "Pugad Baboy",
        "Trese",
        "Sskait",
        "Arkitekyuklid"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What modern comic was created by Budjette Tan and Kajo Baldisimo?",
      "answer": "Trese",
      "choices": [
        "Trese",
        "Sskait",
        "Arkitekyuklid",
        "Pugad Baboy"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the creator of the online comic “Sskait”?",
      "answer": "AJ Bacar",
      "choices": [
        "AJ Bacar",
        "John Euclid Templonuevo",
        "Budjette Tan",
        "Washington “Tonton” Young"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the creator of the online comic “Arkitekyuklid”?",
      "answer": "John Euclid Templonuevo",
      "choices": [
        "John Euclid Templonuevo",
        "AJ Bacar",
        "Budjette Tan",
        "Washington “Tonton” Young"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What has been shown to have an innate ability to influence, convince, and even enrage listeners?",
      "answer": "power of radio",
      "choices": [
        "power of radio",
        "telegraph",
        "podcast",
        "iPod and broadcast"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What went live in 1837, establishing a precedent for modern electronic means of communicating across borders?",
      "answer": "telegraph",
      "choices": [
        "telegraph",
        "power of radio",
        "podcast",
        "iPod and broadcast"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who constructed a high-frequency transformer, an important component of electronic transmitters, in 1891?",
      "answer": "Nikola Tesla",
      "choices": [
        "Nikola Tesla",
        "Guglielmo Marconi",
        "Johannes Gutenberg",
        "Henry Hermann"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was ready to transmit the first radio transmission in 1895?",
      "answer": "Guglielmo Marconi",
      "choices": [
        "Guglielmo Marconi",
        "Nikola Tesla",
        "Johannes Gutenberg",
        "Henry Hermann"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What did Guglielmo Marconi refer to his invention as, since its signal traveled in all directions, i.e., radially, from the transmission point?",
      "answer": "radiotelegraph",
      "choices": [
        "radiotelegraph",
        "telegraph",
        "power of radio",
        "podcast"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who owned the first three fifty-watt stations, two of which were in Manila and one near Pasay City?",
      "answer": "Henry Hermann",
      "choices": [
        "Henry Hermann",
        "Guglielmo Marconi",
        "Nikola Tesla",
        "Johannes Gutenberg"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the call signs of the first three fifty-watt stations owned by Henry Hermann?",
      "answer": "KZKZ, KZRM, and KZEG",
      "choices": [
        "KZKZ, KZRM, and KZEG",
        "KZRQ, KZRM, and DZMM",
        "DZMM,KZKZ nad KZEG",
        "AZRM, KZKZ, and DZMM"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the daily fares on most stations in the Philippines, heavily favored by the masses, whether urban or rural?",
      "answer": "Radio dramas and commentaries",
      "choices": [
        "Radio dramas and commentaries",
        "The ‘pang-masa’",
        "podcast",
        "radiocast"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a show which tackles clichéd storylines about abused women, philandering spouses, love’s inequity, and dishonesty?",
      "answer": "The ‘pang-masa’",
      "choices": [
        "The ‘pang-masa’",
        "Radio dramas and commentaries",
        "podcast",
        "radiocast"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a rising media format for delivering radio-style information and programs to a computer, phone, or media device?",
      "answer": "podcast",
      "choices": [
        "podcast",
        "The ‘pang-masa’",
        "Radio dramas and commentaries",
        "radiocast"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a combination of iPod and broadcast?",
      "answer": "iPod and broadcast",
      "choices": [
        "iPod and broadcast",
        "iPod and Casting",
        "iPad and Cast",
        "Product and broadcast"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What are comparable to regular radio programs in that they tend to be chat shows and informational programs on certain themes?",
      "answer": "Podcasts",
      "choices": [
        "Podcasts",
        "iPod and broadcast",
        "Radiocasts",
        "Radio dramas and commentaries"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of Joe Rogan’s podcast?",
      "answer": "The Joe Rogan Experience",
      "choices": [
        "The Joe Rogan Experience",
        "Good Mythical Morning",
        "Wag Kang Lilingon",
        "Paano Ba To?"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who are the duo behind the podcast “Good Mythical Morning”?",
      "answer": "Rhett McLaughlin and Charles Lincoln “Link” Neal III",
      "choices": [
        "Rhett McLaughlin and Charles Lincoln “Link” Neal III",
        "Grace Marcellana and Mimai Cabungson",
        "Joe Rogan",
        "Bianca Gonzales"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the podcast by the duo Grace Marcellana and Mimai Cabungson?",
      "answer": "‘Wag Kang Lilingon",
      "choices": [
        "‘Wag Kang Lilingon",
        "Good Mythical Morning",
        "The Joe Rogan Experience",
        "Paano Ba To?"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the podcast by celebrity Bianca Gonzales?",
      "answer": "Paano Ba To?",
      "choices": [
        "Paano Ba To?",
        "‘Wag Kang Lilingon",
        "Good Mythical Morning",
        "The Joe Rogan Experience"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who invented the first phonograph in 1877?",
      "answer": "Thomas Edison",
      "choices": [
        "Nikola Tesla",
        "Johann Sebastian Bach",
        "Elvis Presley",
        "Thomas Edison"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the phonograph that was invented a decade after Thomas Edison’s original design?",
      "answer": "flat-disk phonograph",
      "choices": [
        "Indie Music",
        "Gospel",
        "Electronic",
        "flat-disk phonograph"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which genre includes the works of eminent composers like Johann Sebastian Bach and Ludwig van Beethoven?",
      "answer": "Classical Music",
      "choices": [
        "Country",
        "Disco",
        "Rock",
        "Classical Music"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which genre encompasses all subgenres, including traditional, urban, and rock country?",
      "answer": "Country",
      "choices": [
        "Classical Music",
        "Adult contemporary",
        "Experimental",
        "Country"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which genre is a blend of classics, light opera, and softer rock singles?",
      "answer": "Adult contemporary",
      "choices": [
        "Disco",
        "Folk",
        "Jazz and Blues",
        "Adult contemporary"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which genre is divided into classic ____ from the 1970s and 1980s and contemporary techno or electronic dance music (EDM)?",
      "answer": "Disco",
      "choices": [
        "Electic Pop",
        "Gospel",
        "Opera",
        "Disco"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which genre is a mash-up of several genres, including pop, rap, rock, techno, and others?",
      "answer": "Electic Pop",
      "choices": [
        "Electronic",
        "Experimental",
        "Rap and hip-hop",
        "Electic Pop"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which genre incorporates electronic effects and digital instruments?",
      "answer": "Electronic",
      "choices": [
        "Folk",
        "Rhythm and Blues, Funk, and Soul",
        "Rock",
        "Electronic"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which genre uses non-musical objects to create traditional instruments or sounds?",
      "answer": "Experimental",
      "choices": [
        "Indie Music",
        "Classical Music",
        "Country",
        "Experimental"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which genre employs the use of traditional musical instruments?",
      "answer": "Folk",
      "choices": [
        "Adult contemporary",
        "Disco",
        "Electic Pop",
        "Folk"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which genre allows people to reflect on their spirituality and get in touch with their inner ethos?",
      "answer": "Gospel",
      "choices": [
        "Electronic",
        "Experimental",
        "Jazz and Blues",
        "Gospel"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which genre includes music from all eras and genres of jazz, blues, and swing?",
      "answer": "Jazz and Blues",
      "choices": [
        "Opera",
        "Rap and hip-hop",
        "Rhythm and Blues, Funk, and Soul",
        "Jazz and Blues"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which genre mostly includes works from the romantic period?",
      "answer": "Opera",
      "choices": [
        "Rock",
        "Indie Music",
        "Thomas Edison",
        "Opera"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which genre includes classic and contemporary works by rap and hip-hop artists?",
      "answer": "Rap and hip-hop",
      "choices": [
        "flat-disk phonograph",
        "Classical Music",
        "Country",
        "Rap and hip-hop"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which genre includes classic and contemporary performers performing rhythm and blues music, as well as its funk and soul subgenres?",
      "answer": "Rhythm and Blues, Funk, and Soul",
      "choices": [
        "Adult contemporary",
        "Disco",
        "Electic Pop",
        "Rhythm and Blues, Funk, and Soul"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which genre encompasses all styles of music, past, and present, including old rock and roll, classic rock and roll, jazz rock, folk rock, hard rock, metal rock, industrial rock, grunge, and punk?",
      "answer": "Rock",
      "choices": [
        "Electronic",
        "Experimental",
        "Folk",
        "Rock"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which genre began in the late 1980s in the United Kingdom and has since developed into its own distinct genres, including Britpop and Riot Grrrl, among others?",
      "answer": "Indie Music",
      "choices": [
        "Gospel",
        "Jazz and Blues",
        "Opera",
        "Indie Music"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of traditional music in the Philippines is mostly based on the syntactic structure of a Malayan language and connected with village feasts, family activities, and the belief in spirits?",
      "answer": "Pre-Hispanic or Malayan-type music",
      "choices": [
        "Hispanic-type Music",
        "Film",
        "Sony Betamax tape",
        "Pre-Hispanic or Malayan-type music"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which type of music in the Philippines is associated with Spanish culture and is often played or accompanied by a plucked-string orchestra?",
      "answer": "Hispanic-type Music",
      "choices": [
        "Pre-Hispanic or Malayan-type music",
        "photography",
        "narrative film",
        "Hispanic-type Music"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is based on photographic technology and includes types such as narrative, documentary, and animated films?",
      "answer": "Film",
      "choices": [
        "Pre-Hispanic or Malayan-type music",
        "Hispanic-type Music",
        "Sony Betamax tape",
        "Film"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What was invented by French scientist Joseph Nicéphore Niépce and later developed by Louis J. M. Daguerre and William Henry Fox Talbot?",
      "answer": "photography",
      "choices": [
        "Film",
        "Pre-Hispanic or Malayan-type music",
        "Hispanic-type Music",
        "photography"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which type of film is a work of fiction or a portrayal of actual events and goes through stages of preproduction, production, and postproduction?",
      "answer": "narrative film",
      "choices": [
        "documentary",
        "Animated films",
        "genre analysis",
        "narrative film"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which type of film depicts real-life circumstances with people explaining their thoughts and experiences to a camera or interviewer?",
      "answer": "documentary",
      "choices": [
        "narrative film",
        "Animated films",
        "genre analysis",
        "documentary"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which type of films are narrative stories intended for children and are often created digitally today?",
      "answer": "Animated films",
      "choices": [
        "narrative film",
        "documentary",
        "genre analysis",
        "Animated films"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an important component of pop culture studies and is often used in scripts for films?",
      "answer": "genre analysis",
      "choices": [
        "Animated films",
        "narrative film",
        "documentary",
        "genre analysis"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What was the first commercialized home video viewing technology, introduced in the late 1970s?",
      "answer": "Sony Betamax tape",
      "choices": [
        "genre analysis",
        "Animated films",
        "narrative film",
        "Sony Betamax tape"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What was the first Filipino film to win an international award in 1937?",
      "answer": "Zamboanga",
      "choices": [
        "Panorama de Manila",
        "Salon de Pertierra",
        "Sony Betamax tape",
        "Zamboanga"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What did local filmmaker Antonio Ramos shoot in 1898 using a Lumiere camera?",
      "answer": "Panorama de Manila",
      "choices": [
        "Zamboanga",
        "Salon de Pertierra",
        "Sony Betamax tape",
        "Panorama de Manila"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where was a 60mm Gaumont Chrono-photograph projector used to show the first four French films in the Philippines on January 1, 1897?",
      "answer": "Salon de Pertierra",
      "choices": [
        "Panorama de Manila",
        "Zamboanga",
        "Fiesta de Quiapo",
        "Salon de Pertierra"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What was the first television station to broadcast in the Philippines in 1953?",
      "answer": "DZAQ-TV Channel 3",
      "choices": [
        "Chronicle Broadcasting Network",
        "Cable television",
        "Philippine Children’s Television Foundation",
        "DZAQ-TV Channel 3"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which broadcasting network was officially born in 1956 when the Lopezes purchased the first television station in the Philippines?",
      "answer": "Chronicle Broadcasting Network",
      "choices": [
        "DZAQ-TV Channel 3",
        "Cable television",
        "Philippine Children’s Television Foundation",
        "Chronicle Broadcasting Network"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What has had the most rapid expansion in the television business and was established in 1969?",
      "answer": "Cable television",
      "choices": [
        "community antenna TV",
        "Netflix",
        "Batibot",
        "Cable television"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of TV networks have been installed to receive broadcast signals from Manila-based stations?",
      "answer": "community antenna TV",
      "choices": [
        "DZAQ-TV Channel 3",
        "Chronicle Broadcasting Network",
        "Cable television",
        "community antenna TV"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which foundation has made it possible to produce world-class educational children’s shows in the Philippines?",
      "answer": "Philippine Children’s Television Foundation",
      "choices": [
        "ABS Foundation",
        "Music Foundation",
        "Children Foundation",
        "Philippine Children’s Television Foundation"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the award-winning show for elementary school students produced by the Philippine Children’s Television Foundation?",
      "answer": "Batibot",
      "choices": [
        "Netflix",
        "Nintendo",
        "advertere",
        "Batibot"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an entertainment corporation created in 1997 that specializes in streaming media and video-on-demand?",
      "answer": "Netflix",
      "choices": [
        "Batibot",
        "Nintendo",
        "advertere",
        "Netflix"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Japanese firm took over and improved gaming technology while producing iconic adventure games like Donkey Kong and the Super Mario Brothers?",
      "answer": "Nintendo",
      "choices": [
        "Netflix",
        "Batibot",
        "advertere",
        "Nintendo"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What term, derived from the medieval Latin verb, is defined as “to direct one’s attention to”?",
      "answer": "advertere",
      "choices": [
        "Nintendo",
        "Netflix",
        "Batibot",
        "advertere"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which advertising technique uses unconscious archetypal motifs to construct a commercial image?",
      "answer": "Mythologization",
      "choices": [
        "Aestheticization",
        "Real-life advertising",
        "Simulative advertising",
        "Mythologization"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which advertising technique refers to the application of visual artists’ practices?",
      "answer": "Aestheticization",
      "choices": [
        "Mythologization",
        "Real-life advertising",
        "Simulative advertising",
        "Aestheticization"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which advertising technique uses real people and celebrities instead of professional actors?",
      "answer": "Real-life advertising",
      "choices": [
        "Aestheticization",
        "Mythologization",
        "Simulative advertising",
        "Real-life advertising"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which advertising technique is the utilization of popular culture styles, trends, and language to construct advertising messages?",
      "answer": "Simulative advertising",
      "choices": [
        "Real-life advertising",
        "Aestheticization",
        "Mythologization",
        "Simulative advertising"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a sort of subliminal advertising, impacting people’s thinking without their knowledge?",
      "answer": "Placement",
      "choices": [
        "Simulative advertising",
        "Real-life advertising",
        "Aestheticization",
        "Placement"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term for the logical abbreviation of a word or phrase used in digital communication?",
      "answer": "Textspeak",
      "choices": [
        "Swardspeak",
        "Syllabic substitution",
        "Inversion",
        "Textspeak"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term for the language that incorporates various languages and names in creative ways, originally a coded language for the gay community?",
      "answer": "Swardspeak",
      "choices": [
        "Textspeak",
        "Syllabic substitution",
        "Inversion",
        "Swardspeak"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term for changing one syllable to a word to give it a new form unique only to those who know them?",
      "answer": "Syllabic substitution",
      "choices": [
        "Textspeak",
        "Swardspeak",
        "Inversion",
        "Syllabic substitution"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term for the deliberate switching of either the word’s entire spelling or syllabic placement?",
      "answer": "Inversion",
      "choices": [
        "Textspeak",
        "Swardspeak",
        "Syllabic substitution",
        "Inversion"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term for the intentional use of words that have localized versions of the intended words, usually in the form of puns?",
      "answer": "Word plays",
      "choices": [
        "Textspeak",
        "Swardspeak",
        "Syllabic substitution",
        "Word plays"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term for the usage of words that sound similar to the words that will be used in the conversation, mostly through the use of foreign words whose phonetics have a similar version to the local words?",
      "answer": "Deliberate homophones",
      "choices": [
        "Textspeak",
        "Swardspeak",
        "Syllabic substitution",
        "Deliberate homophones"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term for the intentional use of famous celebrity names, whether local or foreign, as descriptors for the intended words?",
      "answer": "Name puns",
      "choices": [
        "Textspeak",
        "Swardspeak",
        "Syllabic substitution",
        "Name puns"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term for the deliberate usage of foreign words while retaining the foreign word’s meaning?",
      "answer": "Borrowing",
      "choices": [
        "Textspeak",
        "Swardspeak",
        "Syllabic substitution",
        "Borrowing"
      ]
    }
  ]
}
